<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wlcpeu on ifconfig.it</title>
    <link>http://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/tags/wlcpeu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wlcpeu on ifconfig.it</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2014 09:13:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/tags/wlcpeu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireless LAN Professionals Conference Europe</title>
      <link>http://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/wlcpeu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2014 09:13:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/wlcpeu/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Last week I had the opportunity to attend the first &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wlanprosconference.com/&#34;&gt;Wireless LAN Professionals Conference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wireless is an important part of my job, I designed and managed more than a few wireless networks installations and I know there are many challenges involved, I felt I needed to increase my knowledge so I had pretty high expectations from this event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://assets.amuniversal.com/22e412106cba01301d46001dd8b71c47&#34; alt=&#34;ALT&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The schedule included two tracks of 8 sessions each and ten &amp;ldquo;Ten Talks&amp;rdquo; in one day and a half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many aspects of the event that I really liked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-is-not-a-vendor-event&#34;&gt;It is not a vendor event&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course vendors were present, many speakers work for a vendors. The good part is the sessions were not just presentation of products but wireless concepts, best practices, installation advices, protocol behaviour that can be applied to any vendor, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ieee802.org/11/&#34;&gt;802.11&lt;/a&gt; is a standard right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-attendee-bag&#34;&gt;The attendee bag&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every attendee of the conference receive a bag with many gadgets (AP, survey software, spectrum analyzer) that worth the price of the conference itself. That can be a strong argument for an employee to get the authorization from a manager to attend the event and in my case I use these material to study and do some test labs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;social&#34;&gt;Social&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why attend an event like this in person instead of just watching the videos later? Simply because we need face-by-face conversations to share experiences, to know we&amp;rsquo;re not alone fighting for a proper design and survey, technology can&amp;rsquo;t replace human interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course the event has its &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23WLPC_EU&amp;amp;src=typd&#34;&gt;Twitter hastag&lt;/a&gt; and many discussions are very interesting but connecting a Twitter account to an actual face and voice really makes a difference to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wrap-up&#34;&gt;Wrap up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was great to attend &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wlanprosconference.com/&#34;&gt;WLCP&lt;/a&gt; and of course I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to attend again to this event. I took a lot of notes during the sessions and added many wireless professionals to my list in Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My job is not focused on wifi only so I don&amp;rsquo;t expect to reach the level of expertise of other attendees but it was good to know that I did pretty well in my installations so far, that is a big motivation to keep studying &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cwnp.com/&#34;&gt;CWNP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you next year in WLCP!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>