<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wifi on ifconfig.it</title>
    <link>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/tags/wifi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wifi on ifconfig.it</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/tags/wifi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>WiFi security 4 dummies</title>
      <link>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/2016-04-04-wifisec4dummies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/2016-04-04-wifisec4dummies/</guid>
      <description>Customer site, their security policy for WiFi is an SSID with a secret PSK: the IT manager type the password on my PC to allow me to access the network.
Maybe he&amp;rsquo;s not aware of my keylogger or that the password con be easily retrieved in cleartext. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how.
Windows 10: retrieve the WiFi PSK in cleartext Show a list of all WiFi profiles configured on the PC:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WLPC 2015 @ Berlin</title>
      <link>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/2015-10-30-wlpc-2015-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/2015-10-30-wlpc-2015-berlin/</guid>
      <description>For the second year in a row I attended Wireless Lan Professionals Conference Europe, this time in Berlin.
Location The choice of location this time was much better, last year I went to Maastrich through Brussels, most people didn&amp;rsquo;t liked it since it&amp;rsquo;s not easy to reach.
The sessions Session quality is high, mostly vendor neutral, speakers are well prepared and willing to share their knowledge and experiences.
Last year there were more sessions splitted in two different rooms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meraki CMNA</title>
      <link>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/2015-03-04-cmna/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/2015-03-04-cmna/</guid>
      <description>Today I&amp;rsquo;ve attended a Meraki technical training course at Cisco offices.
The training was organized in short presentations of product features followed by hands-on labs based on all the products available today.
I was suprised to find not only people from small companies or system integrators but more that 50% of the attendees were from Cisco Gold Partners sent to evaluate the products for &amp;ldquo;managed network&amp;rdquo; services. Cloud managed network gear is quite a hot topic today and I expect many projects in the future will involve this kind of solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireless LAN Professionals Conference Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/2014-10-18-wlcpeu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/2014-10-18-wlcpeu/</guid>
      <description>Last week I had the opportunity to attend the first Wireless LAN Professionals Conference in Europe.
Wireless is an important part of my job, I designed and managed more than a few wireless networks installations and I know there are many challenges involved, I felt I needed to increase my knowledge so I had pretty high expectations from this event.
The schedule included two tracks of 8 sessions each and ten &amp;ldquo;Ten Talks&amp;rdquo; in one day and a half.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antenna radiation pattern, law of sines, free space propagation loss</title>
      <link>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/2013-04-20-wifi-law-of-sines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/2013-04-20-wifi-law-of-sines/</guid>
      <description>I work with WiFi more than I admit to myself and now that I have more time to study outside the CCIE R&amp;amp;S blueprint boundaries it&amp;rsquo;s time to focus on other technologies.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved in an interesting high density WiFi project and after a successfull deployment there&amp;rsquo;re some things I&amp;rsquo;d like to check. As Cisco partner my company had support for the network design from the same team involved in London Olympics and Cisco Live!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCIEWireless blog and Youtube Channel</title>
      <link>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/cciewireless-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/cciewireless-blog/</guid>
      <description>A great blog and Youtube channel with a lot of resources for Cisco Wireless:
[youtube]http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y6gxNMo3CW4&amp;amp;list=UUm3YBBhcJRokmAD1LaJg3hQ&amp;amp;index=1&amp;amp;feature=plcp[/youtube]</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>