<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work on ifconfig.it</title>
    <link>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/tags/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work on ifconfig.it</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Is more technology good for your business?</title>
      <link>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/ismoretechgoodforbusiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/ismoretechgoodforbusiness/</guid>
      <description>I read this post on Ivan&amp;rsquo;s blog this morning and as often happens it made me think.
The key point is: figure out what your most pressing problem is.
Who should do that? Let&amp;rsquo;s analyze the roles involved in a typical SMB or enterprise.
Vendors Vendors have just one target: sell their products. They can&amp;rsquo;t really customize the product to every business needs so they try to convince the customer the problem their product solve is the problem you have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opportunistic Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/opportunisticlearning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/opportunisticlearning/</guid>
      <description>I got inspired by the book &amp;ldquo;The 1 Thing&amp;ldquo; and changed a little bit my behavior about work and training I&amp;rsquo;d like to share here to discuss and improve.
The Background A while ago one guy could setup a bunch of physical servers, install/configure/manage OS, configure network equipment and setup a firewall to connect to the internet.
For some specific software platforms the support of the vendor for installation and maintenance was enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking work</title>
      <link>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/2010-12-07-hacking-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/2010-12-07-hacking-work/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Breaking stupid rules for smart results.&amp;rdquo;
 Not the best book ever but I liked the concept: don&amp;rsquo;t stick to the rules if you feel the rules don&amp;rsquo;t allows to work in and efficient way.
Hacking work is actually intrapreneurship and requires a little anarchic spirit. How can we improve if we never try something different?
Good reads:
 Moxie Marlinspike - We should all have something to hide</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>