<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker on ifconfig.it</title>
    <link>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/tags/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker on ifconfig.it</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker join the dots</title>
      <link>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/2015-05-25-docker-join-the-dots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/2015-05-25-docker-join-the-dots/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series about Docker, including:
 Docker Introduction
 Docker: Install software inside a container
 Docker Volumes
 Docker Networking - bridge container to host NIC
  We started with the basics and moved on with adding software, using volumes and then bridging a container to the network.
As a said I&amp;rsquo;m neither a developer or a system administrator, I work as Network Engineer so I&amp;rsquo;m not the main target for Docker but I found it very useful for a specific need and now it&amp;rsquo;s time to join the dots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker networking bridge to host NIC</title>
      <link>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/2015-05-18-docker-networking-bridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/2015-05-18-docker-networking-bridge/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series about Docker, including:
 Docker Introduction
 Docker: Install software inside a container
 Docker Volumes
  Today we&amp;rsquo;ll see Docker networking with a very specific target in mind: bridge container to the host network.
This isn&amp;rsquo;t supposed to be the way of work of containers: a container should be created to run a single application so container networking, from the point of view of a Network Engineer, is essentialy a Port Address Translation with a firewall exception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Volumes</title>
      <link>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/2015-05-12-docker-volumes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/2015-05-12-docker-volumes/</guid>
      <description>In the last post we saw that any filesystem change inside a docker container is lost if not commited to the image.
What if we want to share data between containers?
We can use Docker&amp;rsquo;s Data Volumes and Data Volume Containers.
Data Volumes or Data Volume Containers? Data Volumes feature allows us to mount a local directory from the host inside a container. That looks good but somehow it breaks the concept of isolation between host and container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Install software inside a container</title>
      <link>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/2015-05-07-docker-installsw/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/2015-05-07-docker-installsw/</guid>
      <description>In the first post of this series we left with a running Ubuntu 15.04 container.
Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to install software inside the container.
A container is &amp;ldquo;stateless&amp;rdquo;, meaning any file change inside a container is lost when the container is closed, including software installations.
Install software To install software inside a container any method supported for the Linux distribution is fine.
I usually install Python 2.7, iftop, htop, tmux so let&amp;rsquo;s run a container:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/2015-05-04-docker-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/2015-05-04-docker-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Docker and more generic Linux containers technology are a hot topic these days. The website says &amp;ldquo;for developers and sysadmins&amp;rdquo;, I am neither of the two but I can still find some useful applications for containers as a Network Engineer.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start from the basics.
Install docker and first run We can apt-get to install docker on Ubuntu Linux:
apt-get install docker.io  Now start docker service:
service docker start  That was easy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>