<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nfd16 on ifconfig.it</title>
    <link>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/tags/nfd16/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nfd16 on ifconfig.it</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/tags/nfd16/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NFD16 day two - Cisco Project Starship a.k.a. Intersight</title>
      <link>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/nfd16day2ciscostartship/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/nfd16day2ciscostartship/</guid>
      <description>Day two of NFD16 with Cisco. The presentation was split in two parts. First part for Intersight, second part for Tetration.
I&amp;rsquo;ll post here just a few thoughts about Intersight.
Merakify all the servers! What&amp;rsquo;s Cisco Intersight? If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with cloud-managed devices like Meraki the concept is quite similar.
A Cisco server runs the Device Connector client that links to a central management portal that runs on Cisco DC SaaS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFD16 day two - Apstra</title>
      <link>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/nfd16day2apstra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/nfd16day2apstra/</guid>
      <description>Day two of NFD16 started with Apstra and their intent-based networking system.
Intent concept is not as broad as SDN but still vendors have different views of this meaning.
According to Apstra an intent is &amp;ldquo;the definition of the expected outcome&amp;rdquo;. The sum of the intents of a network is the source of truth.
Read Sasha Ratkovic blog post about the definition of Intent Based Networking. The checklist he suggest can be very useful to compare different solutions and spot intent washing strategies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFD16 day one - Arista</title>
      <link>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/nfd16day1arista/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/nfd16day1arista/</guid>
      <description>Second part of Tech Field Day NFD16 day 1 continues with Arista.
Getting ready for @AristaNetworks #NFD16 pic.twitter.com/SCWXVGsR2l
&amp;mdash; Gian Paolo (@gp_ifconfig) September 13, 2017  Arista&amp;rsquo;s presentation included 400G (hist: it&amp;rsquo;s fast!), EOS programmability, Network Automation and Telemetry, Routing Architecture Transformations.
All video recording are in the youtube channel of TechFielDay.
EOS Programmability Ken Duda (Founder, CTO, and Senior VP of Software Engineering) did a great session about EOS programmability explaining the reason of some technical choices and the available options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFD16 day one - Veriflow</title>
      <link>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/nfd16day1veriflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ifconfig.it/hugo/post/nfd16day1veriflow/</guid>
      <description>First day at Tech Field Day NFD16, I&amp;rsquo;m quite excited to be here among fellow network engineers to share our views on products and technologies.
I&amp;rsquo;m planning to post my takeaways for each vendor with variable lengths based on my knowledge and interest of the specific product.
Today&amp;rsquo;s first presenter is Veriflow. Let&amp;rsquo;s see what Continuous Network Verification is and how it can help to make networks more robust and secure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>